Mark C. McFadden

13 Ironstone Circle

Erlanger, KY 41018 Phone: 859-750-1953

http://www.markmcfadden.net

Blog: http://msquaredwebsvc.blogspot.com/

E-Mail: m2web@yahoo.com Twitter: http://twitter.com/m2web

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Fifteen years experience in the Information Technologies field specializing in the skills of Internet technologies, Network Administration, ASP/Visual Basic, .Net and J2EE application design and development. I have designed and implemented several Internet based systems ranging from static "brochureware" sites to dynamic e-commerce solutions. Finally, I have spoken regularly before teams and corporate gatherings educating on various topics and technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML/XHTML
- C#/.Net Development
- Windows NT, IIS 4/5, & Novell Administration
- Photoshop 6
- Classic ASP & ASP.Net
- Basic ABAP
- Flex 3
- Agile Development Methodologies

- Crystal Reports 8.5 & Basic WebFocus Reports
- Ruby and Ruby on Rails 3.x
- Joomla Development
- MeteorJS
- VBScript
- PHP
- Java 1.4 & 1.5 with Struts and Ant
- JavaScript

EDUCATION

Major: Business Informatics

School: Northern Kentucky University

Awarded: Master's in Business Informatics Outstanding Student 2009-2010

Degree: Master of Science in Business Informatics- 3.86 GPA Certificate: Graduate Certificate in Enterprise Resource Planning

Completion Date: 12/2009

Major: Networking & Distributed Systems School: Columbus State Community College

Degree/Certificate: Certified Novell Administrator (CNA) - 3.X

Completion Date: 03/1997

Major: Education
School: Ohio University

Degree/Certificate: Bachelor of Science- Summa Cum Laude

Completion Date: 11/1993

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Employer: Western & Southern Financial Group

Location: Cincinnati, OH

Title: Senior Systems Programmer/Analyst

Duration: 03/2013 – Present

- Developed Java Based Solutions for a New Business Data
 Utilized Websphere Application Server with a DB2 Database
- Constructed Reports from Java to work with a Batch Control Interface API
- Created both Windows Services and Web Services for Service Oriented Architecture
- Utilized Automated Testing Applications such as JUnit for Test Driven Development
- Developed and Presented Demonstrations for New SoftwareFrameworks

Employer: US Bank Location: Cincinnati, OH Title: Application Developer Duration: 11/2000 – 03/2013

- Developed a Java Based Commercial Customer Banking Application
- Combined Ant Build Scripts and JUnit Tests into an automated builds and tests
- Created both Windows Services and Web Services for Service Oriented Architecture
- Utilized Automated Testing Applications such as NUnit for Test Driven Development
- Design of various Intranet Applications with Unified Modeling Language
- Developed web applications utilizing Active Server Pages and Visual Basic COM
- Created Object-Oriented Web based applications on the Microsoft.NET platform with C# and SOL Server
- Lead Development Group in Application Design and Implementation
- Presented Instructional Topics On Development Methodologies and Patterns
- Utilized Rational Tools for Lifecycle Development
- Developed Web Parts for SharePoint Portal Server.
- Created .Net XML Web and Windows Services

Employer: ICES Limited

Location: Air Force Institute of Technology, Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Ohio

Title: Web Administrator *Duration: 08/1999 – 11/2000*

- Setup And Administered Four Dell Power Edge 6300 And 6400 Web Servers
- Setup And Administered Internet Information Server 4 And 5 Servers
- Create Active Server Page Web Applications With VB Script, Javascript, And Database Connectivity
- Design And Execution Of MS Access And SQL Server Databases
- Setup And Administered Microsoft Proxy Server
- Supported And Managed Fifteen Web Authors For More Than Twenty Different Web Sites

Employer: PIC 17 Workforce Board

Location: Circleville, Ohio

Title: Systems Administration/Web Developer

Duration: 05/1995 – 08/1999

- Administered Citrix Winframe 1.7 Server With A Custom SQL Server 6.5 Application
- Designed And Provided Training On Various Software Tools And Web Page Creation
- Setup And Administered Linux Red Hat 6 File Server Within A NT 4 Environment
- Created Custom Built Web Based Database Application And Related Manuals and Windows Based Help Files
- Planned, Deployed, And Evaluated Network Hardware And Software Solutions for the Various Partner Agencies
- Supported End Users With Hardware And Software Needs And Problems
- Chaired And Facilitated An Inter-agency Electronic Connectivity Project Consisting Of Twenty Separate Agencies

Employer: Great Oaks Institute of Technology

Location: Washington CH, Ohio

Title: Adult Education Computer Instructor (Part Time)

Duration: 09/1997 - 08/1999

- Taught adult students basic computer applications and use of Microsoft Office 95 and 97 Suite Applications
- Taught students in Internet Usage of Web Browsers, E-mail Clients, and News Group Readers.

Employer: Great Oaks Institute of Technology (OakWeb Community Internet)

Location: Washington CH, Ohio

Title: System Administrator/Webmaster (Volunteer)

Duration: 08/1995 - 09/1997

- Created and managed Web site on Sun Spare V System
- Monitored and maintained Unix BSD system activity
- Conducted public presentations for Community Network and Internet promotion
- Instructed on Internet use and Web Page creation with JavaScript and HTML

Employer: Southern State Community College

Location: Washington CH, Ohio

Title: Computer Instructor (Part Time)

Duration: 06/1995 - 09/1995

Taught college students basic computer science principles, desktop publishing, and word processing